Preliminary Guide to the American Economic Association Records, 1886-2008 and undated RL.00033
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Accession (2001-0118)
  - Secretary-Treasurer Files, 1949-1980s; 1
    - Carter Committee, 1976 (Box 933)
      Includes documents related to Carter's presidential campaign and economic policy
    - Budget and Planning Committee, 1971-1984; 2 folders (Box 933)
    - Advisory Committee on the Structure of the Profession, 1971-1972 (Box 933)
    - Advisory Committee on Studies of the Labor Market for Economists, 1974-1978 (Box 933)
    - Select Committee on Afro-American Affairs, 1975-1976 (Box 933)
      Includes documents related to meeting scheduling
    - Committee on the Education and Training of Minority Group Economists, 1970-1974; 2 folders (Box 933)
      Includes committee reports and correspondence related to committee business
    - Ad Hoc Committee to Review New Proposed Standard Occupational Classification System, 1976-1980 (Box 933)
    - Advisory Committee on Clearinghouse for Research in Economics, 1970-1984 (Box 933)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Publishing Contracts, 1979-1982 (Box 933)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1970-1983 (Box 933)
      Includes documents pertaining to association relationship with the Social Science Research Council
    - Advisory Committee to National Commission on Employment and Unemployment Statistics, 1978-1981 (Box 934)
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Publication, 1982-1983 (Box 934)
    - Advisory Committee on Historical Diplomatic Documentation (State Department), 1981 (Box 934)
      Includes documents related to Association's nomination of a member to serve on advisory committee to the US Department of State
    - Committees - Miscellaneous, 1976-1979 (Box 934)
      Includes correspondence related to various Association committees
    - Committee Appointments - Miscellaneous, 1970-1976 (Box 934)
      Includes correspondence related to appointments to various Association committees
    - Ad Hoc Committee on Evaluating Minority Recruitment, 1978-1979 (Box 934)
    - Summer Program for Minority Students, 1982 (Box 934)
    - Committee on the Status of Minority Groups, 1972-1982 (Box 934)
      Includes documents for committee appointments and activities related to expanding recruitment and opportunities for members of minority groups in the economics profession
    - Committee on US-China Exchanges, 1975-1980 (Box 934)
    - Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), 1981-1984; 2 folders (Box 934)
      Includes newsletters, annual report, and correspondence
    - Committee on US-Soviet Exchanges, 1975-1984; 2 folders (Box 934)
    - Fritz Machlup Presidential Address, 1966 (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0001)
    - Gotfried Haberler Presidential Address, 1963 (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0002)
    - AEA, undated (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0003)
    - Presidential Address and Business Meeting, 1977 (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0004)
    - AEA, undated (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0005)
    - James Tobin, Richard T. Ely Lecture (Tape 1), 1963 (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0006)
    - James Tobin, Richard T. Ely Lecture (Tape 2), 1963 (Box 935, Item RL00033-RR-0007)
    - Committee on Policy Communication, 1971-1973 (Box 936)
    - Committee on Hiring Practices, 1972-1974 (Box 936)
    - Committee on the Journals: American Economic Review and Journal of Economic Literature, 1973-1974 (Box 936)
    - Nominating Committee, 1970-1984; 6 folders (Box 936)
    - Executive Committee, 1981-1983 (Box 936)
    - Executive Committee, 1983-1985; 5 folders (Box 937)
    - Committee on Political Discrimination, 1975-1984; 3 folders (Box 937)
    - Committee on Political Discrimination, 1975-1978 (Box 938)
    - Committee on Publications, 1974-1982; 3 folders (Box 938)
    - Committee on the History of the AEA, 1975-1976 (Box 938)
    - Finance Committee, 1970-1984; 3 folders (Box 938)
    - Committee on Elections, 1970-1984; 3 folders (Box 938)
    - Insurance Committee, 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box 939)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1971-1973; 2 folders (Box 939)
    - Vacancies and Applications, 1973 (Box 939)
      Includes documents related to job postings
    - Papers and Proceedings, 1973-1974; 2 folders (Box 939)
    - Committee on Publications, 1971-1973; 3 folders (Box 939)
    - Pareto Project, 1970-1971; 3 folders (Box 939)
      Includes documents related to publication of Vilfredo Pareto's collected papers in English
    - Pareto Project, 1964-1970; 4 folders (Box 940)
    - Committee on Computerization, 1969-1971; 2 folders (Box 940)
    - Committee on US-Soviet Exchanges, 1973-1983; 3 folders (Box 940)
    - Rockefeller Foundation, 1957-1959 (Box 941)
      Includes files related to grant for publishing Association journals
    - Ritter Fund, 1952-1958 (Box 941)
      Includes files related to reprinting articles from the American Economic Review
    - American Economic Review, 1961-1970 (Box 941)
    - Arthur Andersen Co., 1969-1980 (Box 941)
      Includes files related to Association finances
    - Asia Foundation, 1970-1979; 10 folders (Box 941)
      Includes files related to grant funding to expand participation of Asian economists and students in Association
    - Asia Foundation, 1966-1971; 3 folders (Box 942)
    - American Economic Review, 1961-1974; 3 folders (Box 942)
    - Nominating Committee, 1972-1978; 2 folders (Box 942)
    - Committee on Elections, 1970-1980; 4 folders (Box 942)
    - Census Advisory Committee, 1965-1969 (Box 942)
    - Committee on Policy Communication, 1972 (Box 943)
    - Committee on Quantitative Data, 1968 (Box 943)
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1970 (Box 943)
    - Committee on the Revision of Handbook, 1969 (Box 943)
    - Committee on Computerization, 1974 (Box 943)
    - Committee on the Status of Minority Groups in the Economics Profession, 1974-1979; 6 folders (Box 943)
      Includes information on summer program for minority students in economics and documents related to grant funding
    - Employment Register, 1963-1972 (Box 943)
    - Executive Committee, 1972-1973 (Box 944)
    - Committee on the Status of Women in the Economics Profession (CSWEP), 1972-1977; 2 folders (Box 944)
    - Secretary-Treasurer's Personal Files, 1973-1975 (Box 944)
    - Encyclopedia of Economics, 1979-1981 (Box 944)
    - Epsilon, 1977-1984 (Box 944)
      Includes documents related to adopting automated membership system
    - Ethical Standards, 1970-1984; 2 folders (Box 944)
      Includes correspondence discussing possible adoption of ethical standards in the economics profession
    - Federal Agencies, 1974-1976 (Box 944)
      Includes correspondence with federal agencies
    - Connecticut College, 1977-1978 (Box 944)
      Includes correspondence related to AEA Visiting Professors program
    - Consortium of Professional Associations for the Study of Teacher Improvement Programs (Conpass), 1970-1972 (Box 945)
    - R.R. Donnelley, 1977-1978 (Box 945)
      Includes documents for agreement to publish Association handbook
    - Opportunities for Economists, 1979 (Box 945)
      Includes correspondence related to job opportunities for undergraduate economics majors
    - Education, 1971-1979 (Box 945)
      Includes documents related to improving undergraduate economics teaching
    - Education and World View Project, 1979 (Box 945)
      Includes routine correspondence
    - Federal Trade Commission, 1974 (Box 945)
    - Committee on the Status of Minority Groups in the Economics Profession, 1974-1978 (Box 945)
      Includes documents related to Ford Foundation funding of Association summer program
    - Foreign Translation Series, 1969-1974 (Box 945)
      Includes correspondence related to publishing translated texts
    - Group Insurance, 1979-1983 (Box 945)
      Includes materials for group insurance offers to the Association
    - Hertz Contract, 1981-1983 (Box 945)
      Includes materials for group discount for members of the Association
    - Insurance Committee, 1973-1976 (Box 945)
    - Integrity in Federal Statistical Services, 1973 (Box 945)
      Includes correspondence about maintaining integrity in hiring practices for federal agencies
    - Investment Information, 1978 (Box 945)
      Includes information related to investment returns
    - Richard D. Irwin, Inc., 1975-1980 (Box 945)
      Includes documents related to Association publications
    - Johnson Reprint Corp, 1980-1982 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to reprinting back issues of Association journals
    - Leontief Resolution, 1978 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to relationships with economists in other countries
    - Lockheed, 1977-1980 (Box 946)
      Includes agreement for developing database for Journal of Economic Literature
    - McPhee, 1975-1978; 2 folders (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to Barbara McPhee serving as an independent contractor related to the ASSA
    - Mailing Lists, 1972-1976 (Box 946)
    - Mailing Wrappers, 1971-1972 (Box 946)
    - Management International Inc., 1971-1972 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to location of ASSA meetings
    - National Endowment for the Humanities, 1981-1982 (Box 946)
    - Pareto Project, 1971-1973 (Box 946)
    - Pending, 1975 (Box 946)
    - Placement Officers Questionnaire, 1976 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to to Association and department placement officers
    - Placement Service, 1976-1983 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to Association job placement service
    - Postmaster - Correspondence, 1970-1980 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to Association mailing
    - Meeting Planners, 1975-1976 (Box 946)
    - Reynolds Securities, 1976 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to finances
    - Royalties, 1973-1981 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to reprinting articles
    - San Jose, 1974-1975 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence related to Department of Economics at San Jose State University appeals to Association for support in dealing with university administration
    - Science Press, 1976-1977 (Box 946)
      Includes correspondence for publication of Association journals
    - JAIPress, 1982-1983 (Box 946)
    - Committee on the Status of Minority Groups in the Economics Profession, 1976 (Box 947)
      Includes documents related to summer program funded by the Smith Richardson Foundation
    - State National Bank, 1970-1978 (Box 947)
    - Visiting Scholars Program, 1971-1982 and undated; 7 folders (Box 947)
    - Fels - General, 1975 (Box 947)
      Includes routine correspondence involving Association Secretary-Treasurer Rendigs Fels
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1972; 2 folders (Box 947)
      Includes correspondence with the Association Executive Committee
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1970-1974; 4 folders (Box 948)
    - Legal Counsel, 1970-1972 (Box 948)
    - Economics Institute, 1970-1974; 3 folders (Box 948)
    - Editors' Luncheon, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 949)
      Includes correspondence related to meeting of editors of various journals in economics
    - Executive Committee, 1971-1974; 7 folders (Box 949)
    - Executive Committee, 1970-1971; 4 folders (Box 950)
    - National Research Council, 1966-1970 (Box 950)
    - National Science Foundation, 1971-1973 (Box 950)
      Includes correspondence about foundation procedures and national register of scientific personnel
    - Other Associations, 1958-1975 (Box 950)
      Includes correspondence with other professional associations
    - Miscellaneous Lists, undated; 2 folders (Box 950)
      Includes various lists of participants in unnamed meetings, events, and other Association business
    - Augustus M. Kelley, 1953-1971 (Box 950)
      Includes correspondence related to Association publications
    - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1964-1970 (Box 951)
      Includes correspondence related to status of economics education
    - Insurance, 1972 (Box 951)
      Includes correspondence about proposed insurance program for Association members
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1955-1971; 4 folders (Box 951)
    - Index of Economics Journals, 1937-1970; 4 folders (Box 951)
      Includes correspondence related to indexing articles in prominent economics journals
    - National Science Foundation, 1970 (Box 951)
      Includes mailing materials for Association members
    - Committee on Elections, 1972 (Box 951)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 951)
      Includes photographs of prominent economists such as James Duesenberry, Robert Heilbroner, Walter Heller, Lawrence Klein, and Richard Ruggles
    - Alphabetical Correspondence: A-I, 1960-1969; 2 folders (Box 951)
      Includes routine correspondence of the Secretary-Treasurer
    - Alphabetical Correspondence: J-Z, 1960-1968; 2 folders (Box 952)
    - Asia Foundation, 1961-1970; 2 folders (Box 952)
      Includes correspondence related to foundation funding of Association programs and travel grants
    - National Science Foundation, 1970 (Box 952)
    - Payments Made for Use of Articles, 1962-1969 (Box 952)
    - Annual Meeting - Prepublication Volume, 1970 (Box 952)
    - Information Booklet, 1970-1971 (Box 952)
      Includes copies of Association booklet documenting publications and events
    - Papers and Abstracts, 1969-1971; 3 folders (Box 953)
      Includes copies of papers presented at Association annual meeting and related correspondence
    - Committee on Elections, 1971 (Box 953)
    - AEA Copyright, 1981-1986 (Box 953)
      Includes correspondence about copyright permissions
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1980-1984; 2 folders (Box 953)
    - Executive Committee, 1987-1989 (Box 953)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1979-1985; 9 folders (Box 954)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1980-1990; 8 folders (Box 955)
    - Journal of Economic Perspectives, 1987 (Box 955)
    - Executive Committee, 1979-1981 (Box 955)
    - Federal Statistics Users Conference, 1971-1983 (Box 956)
      Includes correspondence and materials related to conference
    - International Economic Association, 1981-1984; 3 folders (Box 956)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1980-1991; 5 folders (Box 956)
    - Economics Institute, 1980-1984; 2 folders (Box 957)
    - Committee on US-China Exchanges, 1980-1984 (Box 957)
    - American Council on Education, 1979-1983 (Box 957)
      Includes correspondence
    - American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies, 1979-1983 (Box 957)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1969-1985; 6 folders (Box 957)
      Includes correspondence related to committees on historically underrepresented minorities within Association and other routine correspondence
    - Council and Other Reps., 1978-1983 (Box 957)
      Includes routine correspondence with former representatives of AEA
    - Financial Statements, 1983-1989; 2 folders (Box 957)
    - Financial Statements, 1968-1972 (Box 958)
    - Connecticut Department of Employment Security, 1986 (Box 958)
    - Colorado Department of Employment Security, 1977-1981 (Box 958)
    - George Banta Company, 1970-1978 (Box 958)
      Includes correspondence related to publishing Association journals
    - Journals - Requests, 1983 (Box 958)
      Includes correspondence related to requests for microfilm and databasing of journals
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1969-1983; 4 folders (Box 958)
    - Journal of Economic Literature, 1979-1985; 3 folders (Box 959)
    - Job Openings for Economists, 1975-1983 and undated (Box 959)
    - Index of Economics Journals, 1969-1983 (Box 959)
    - Hinshaw - General, 1977-1982; 4 folders (Box 959)
    - Hinshaw - General, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 960)
    - Fels - General, 1976-1984; 3 folders (Box 960)
    - AEA - General, 1983-1984; 3 folders (Box 960)
    - AEA - General, 1975-1982; 4 folders (Box 961)
    - AEA and Equal Rights Amendment, 1978; 2 folders (Box 961)
      Includes Tjalling Koopmans's files on AEA correspondence regarding meetings in states that had not ratified the Equal Rights Amendment
    - National Institute of Education, 1984 (Box 961)
    - National Institute of Education, 1983 (Box 962)
    - National Science Foundation, 1970-1984; 5 folders (Box 962)
      Includes correspondence related to NSF National Registry and funding opportunities
    - Consortium of Social Science Associations, 1981 (Box 962)
      Includes routine correspondence and newsletters
    - Royal Economic Society, 1979-1982 (Box 962)
      Includes correspondence about arrangement to offer Journal of Economic Literature to Royal Society
    - Transportation and Public Utilities Group, 1971-1976 (Box 962)
      Includes correspondence related to group within the AEA
    - Modern Language Association, 1982-1983 (Box 962)
    - National Council for Social Studies, 1976-1980 (Box 962)
    - National Economic Association, 1975-1982 (Box 962)
      Includes routine correspondence with association that was formerly the Caucus of Black Economists
    - National Science Foundation, 1971-1975 (Box 963)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1970-1981 (Box 963)
      Includes correspondence related to AEA representatives to Academy
    - National Leadership Conference on US-China Relations, 1976 (Box 963)
    - Kutish Files, 1959; 2 folders (Box 963)
      Includes correspondence related to possible case of plagiarism involving AEA journals
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1957-1968; 2 folders (Box 963)
    - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 1968 (Box 963)
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1966 (Box 963)
    - AEA - General, 1970 (Box 963)
    - AEA- History, 1963-1965 (Box 963)
    - American Economic Review, 1949-1969; 4 folders (Box 964)
    - Annual Meeting, 1942-1968; 2 folders (Box 964)
      Includes expense reports
    - Associated Organizations for Teacher Education, 1968 (Box 964)
    - Association Internationale des Sciences Economiques, 1964 (Box 964)
    - Banta, 1966 (Box 964)
    - Boddy Report, 1963 (Box 964)
      Includes reports on salary scales
    - Kenneth E. Boulding, 1967-1969; 2 folders (Box 964)
      Includes correspondence related to Executive Committee and Boulding's service as AEA President
    - AEA Clearinghouse Project, 1963-1968; 2 folders (Box 964)
    - Committee on Academic Freedom, 1950-1961; 2 folders (Box 964)
    - Committee on Classification, 1966-1968 (Box 964)
    - Committee for Economic Development, 1962-1967 (Box 964)
    - Committee on Economic Education, 1955-1964; 3 folders (Box 964)
    - Committee on Elections, 1965-1967; 3 folders (Box 964)
    - Committee on Group Insurance, 1961 (Box 964)
    - Committee on Honorary Members, 1938-1965; 3 folders (Box 964)
    - Committee on Honors and Awards, 1965-1967 (Box 964)
    - Committee on Professional Ethics, 1961-1962 (Box 964)
    - Subscriptions, 1965 (Box 964)
      Includes receipts for AEA journal subscriptions
    - Distinguished Fellows, 1966 (Box 964)
    - Executive Committee, 1968 (Box 964)
    - Executive Committee, 1968 (Box 965)
    - Milton Friedman, 1967 (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence by Friedman in his role as AEA President
    - Houston, Texas, 1971 (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence about the location of the annual conference
    - Fritz Machlup, 1964-1967 (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence by Machlup and others related to his role as AEA President
    - Nominating Committee, 1966-1968 (Box 966)
    - Social Science Research Council, 1966 (Box 966)
    - Trip - HFW, 1967 (Box 966)
      Includes documents related to travel plans of Secretary-Treasurer Harold F. Williamson
    - Papers of Historical Interest, 1969 and undated (Box 966)
      Includes unsorted documents and correspondence related to AEA business
    - Letters to be Written, 1961-1964 (Box 966)
    - Lists of Books and Publications, 1957 (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence with George Banta Co. about Association publications
    - Chicago 1968 - Letters Agreeing with the Decision of KEB to hold the Meetings in Chicago, 2 folders (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence approving of Kenneth E. Boulding's announcement about the location of the annual conference
    - Chicago 1968 - Boycott (Box 966)
      Includes correspondence by AEA members notifying Kenneth E. Boulding that they intend to boycott the annual conference if held in Chicago
    - Chicago 1968 - Letters Requesting that the 1968 Meetings be Moved from Chicago (Box 966)
      Include correspondence to Kenneth E. Boulding requesting the annual conference not be held in Chicago
    - Chicago 1968 - Boycott (Box 967)
      Includes correspondence related to potential boycott of annual conference
    - Chicago 1968 - Correspondence (Box 967)
      Includes correspondence about annual conference
    - American Council of Learned Societies, 1967 (Box 967)
    - American Economic Review, 1967 (Box 967)
    - A.W. Coats, 1965-1970 (Box 967)
      Includes correspondence about Coats writing a monograph on the history of the AEA and his visiting Secretary-Treasurer Harold Williamson
    - Committee on Economic Education, 1966-1968 (Box 967)
    - Distinguished Fellows, 1965 (Box 967)
    - Journal of Economic Abstracts, 1963-1967 (Box 967)
    - Economics Institute, 1968-1972; 3 folders (Box 967)
      Includes correspondence, reports, and supporting materials
    - Receipts, 1970-1971 (Box 967)
      Includes receipts for Association expenses
    - Executive Committee, 1939-1944 (Box 967)
    - Executive Committee, 1962-1970 (Box 968)
    - Finance Committee, 1970 (Box 968)
    - Ford Foundation, 1951-1967 (Box 968)
      Includes correspondence related to grant funding for AEA activities
    - International Economic Association, 1960-1968 (Box 968)
    - National Science Foundation, 1965 (Box 968)
      Includes materials related to National Register
    - Participating Societies and Record Center, 1964-1968 (Box 968)
      Includes correspondence related to other associations participating in National Register
    - Joseph J. Spengler, 1963-1966 (Box 968)
      Includes correspondence by Spengler and others in his role as AEA President
    - Committee on Travel Grants, 1958-1965; 2 folders (Box 968)
    - Pareto Project, 1971-1973 (Box 968)
    - Pareto Project, 1969-1971; 4 folders (Box 969)
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1963-1970; 9 folders (Box 969)
      Includes documents related to publications on agricultural economics, English works available in other languages, macroeconomics, Vilfredo Pareto, price theory, and economic history
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1945-1970; 13 folders (Box 970)
    - Committee on Research and Publications, 1951-1968; 5 folders (Box 971)
    - Committee on Economic Abstracts, 1960-1962 (Box 971)
    - Committee on Freedom of Teaching, Research, and Publication in Economics, 1953 (Box 971)
    - Ford Foundation, 1959-1967; 2 folders (Box 971)
      Includes documents related to funding Association activities
    - Reading Series, 1964-1967 (Box 971)
      Includes routine correspondence with Richard D. Irwin publishers
    - American Economic Review, 1970 (Box 971)
    - Index of Economics Journals, 1963-1966 (Box 971)
    - Midwest Economics Association, 1983 (Box 971)
    - Italian Economic Society, 1982 (Box 971)
    - American Society of Mechanical Engineers - Standing Committee on Transportation, 1971-1977; 2 folders (Box 971)
      Includes correspondence related to inter-society committee
    - Indian Economic Association, 1978-1979 (Box 972)
    - Higher Education Research Institute, 1976 (Box 972)
      Includes correspondence about request to endorse research
    - German Economic Society, 1981-1982 (Box 972)